JOSHUA BURDEN

(402)853-2979 jsh.burd@outlook.com

7812 Harney Street #4 Omaha, Ne 68114

https://github.com/ joshuashepard87

https:// www.linkedin.com/in/ joshua-burden-782a1884

Twitter @adulwulf

Websites

www.westviewbb.com

http:// highlanderomaha.com/

http:// joshuashepard87.github.io /

Profile

I'm a 29 year old Developer using Web Technologies to help build and create beautiful and intrinsic UI/UX designs. I have held many hats in the IT realm and am comfortable with change and welcome innovation. I am a strong team player with good verbal and writing skills. I enjoy challenging roles and always strive to do tasks as quickly and as efficiently as possible.

Experience

Freelance Developer - 2012-Present

Worked with businesses as a consultant for IT infrastructure. From being a trusted advisor to networking with businesses to help build a solid IT environment that is business worthy I have worn many hats. I enjoyed helping with 501C projects for backup disaster recovery to helping build 75 North's highlander project website. I currently remain active helping with my Father's business providing advice on SEO and Internet marketing.

IT Technician, Modis - 2014

Contracted out by Modis staffing under Michael Engelkamp's lead I provided service for Hill Brothers Trucking and Logistics ranging from oversight of Daily Network Operations, Server and VoiP maintenance, Remote troubleshooting, Setup and install of Legacy software across the network, and deploying hardware into the Network environment.

PC Technician- Staples - 2011-2013

While attending Southeast Community College I worked under Tina Andrews performing diagnostics and troubleshooting of computers, hardware, software, and accessories. I was the first line of defense on decisions for repair or replacement of computers and accessories. I performed installation and removal of viruses and malware, and taught customers on IT security.

United States Marine- USMC - 2006-2012

Training in the core competencies of gunnery, combat operations, and battlefield awareness my experience in the USMC gave me several opportunities to practice leadership and perform tasks to improve and maintain operational integrity.

Education

Southeast Community College-Computer Information Technology A.S.

Interface Code School-

Front-end Development & Java

Skills

Java7EE, JavaSE8, HTML, CSS, LESS, SASS, UNIX, JavaScript, Angularjs, Git, Android, Bower, Node.js, MySQL, Photoshop, Windows Server 2012r2, Active Directory

References

Cody Webster - VP of Technology Solution One (402) 861-4001

Brett Faulder - General Manager Misty's Steakhouse (402) 239-8893

Greg Pletcher - Automation Engineer Lease Team, Inc (402) 875-1936

Hobbies

Motorcycles, Cooking, Video Games, Music, Beer Brewing, Drawing, DIY Projects, Pinterest, Bechance, Forums, Dancing, Sports Watching, Firearms, Comedy, Dogs